

## **Thy Nguyen**

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/thynguyenxo/

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a highly motivated and result-driven individual with 3+ years of experience working in the global logistics and information technology consulting industry. I have a strong work ethic and commitment to personal goals and achievements. In my previous roles, I was able to demonstrate extensive knowledge and the ability to utilize a wide range of data analytics and business intelligence tools to aid clients in their business operations and decision-making processes.

## **EDUCATION**

# Master of Science in Management and Technology,

Technical University of Munich October 2023 – present Munich, Germany

# **Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration,** Seattle University September 2016 – June 2018 Seattle, WA, USA

• GPA: 3.6/4.0

• Honors: Cum Laude

 Minor: Entrepreneurship and Innovation

## Semester Abroad,

Maastricht University
August 2017 – December 2017
Maastricht, Limburg, Nederlands

## Associate of Arts in Business Administration, Green River College September 2014 – August 2016 Auburn, WA, USA

• GPA: 3.37/4.0

## Centenary State High School

2011 - 2014 | Brisbane, QLD, Australia

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Career Break, Travel

January 2023 - present

- Taking a 6-month break from my professional experience to enrich my general knowledge through traveling.
- Focus on improving front-end development skills.

## Slalom, Consultant

September 2021 – December 2022 | Seattle, WA, USA

- Worked with a public utility company in Michigan to support the migration effort of 700+ dashboards from Tableau to Power BI and utilized best practice recommendations for Power BI deployment including data governance process, visualization best practice guidelines, and calculation enhancements.
- Collaborated with the internal FinTech BI developer team at Slalom to administer SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) and Power BI paginated report enhancements using Microsoft SQL Management Studio, Visual Studio, and Snowflake.
- Led the research and pilot to migrate paginated reports from SSRS to Power BI Service; designed complex automation flow using Microsoft Power Automate to increase user accessibility and drive stakeholders' usage.
- Developed high-level dashboards based on the principles of Agile SAFe framework for senior executives at a public utility company in San Francisco.
- Managed the content operations for the Azure Synapse Analytics product team at a reputable technology company in the Greater Seattle area.

#### Olafcandles, Owner

July 2018 - December 2022 | Seattle, WA, USA

## Affirma Consulting, Business Analyst

March 2020 - August 2021 | Bellevue, WA, USA

- Worked on a team of 5 business analysts to carry out process improvement initiatives for Microsoft Incentives Operations (MIO).
- Communicated with Microsoft capability managers to define/understand project goals, the scope of work as well as to gather and document technical/functional requirements.
- Analyzed business requirements and translate those into deliverables such as user stories, test scenarios, and supporting artifacts.

## 

## Dean's Honor List, Seattle

University's Albers School of Business and Economics

- Fall quarter (September -December), 2016
- Spring quarter (March June), 2017
- Winter quarter (January March), 2018
- Spring quarter (March June), 2018

## **B** LANGUAGES

English

Vietnamese

German

Dutch



#### **Microsoft Office**

Word, Powerpoint, Excel

#### **Microsoft Excel**

Pivot Tables, VBA, Advanced Formulas

### **Interpersonal Skills**

Teamwork, Written & Verbal
Communication, Organization Skills,
Customer Service

#### **Data Visualization**

Power BI, Power Query, DAX, Tableau

#### Data & Reporting ● ● ● ●

SQL Server Management Studio, Snowflake, Relational Database, Visual Studio

## **Frontend Development**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Tailwind, React, Design Theory, UI/UX

## Agile Project Management ● ● ● ■

Business Analysis, Project Dev Life Cycle, Stakeholder Management, Azure DevOps

- Documented and conducted 3+ stages of functional testing including User Acceptance Testing, Regression Testing, and Quality Assurance Testing prior to the production launch.
- Collaborated effectively with the offshore engineering team to manage expectations, User Story development, and prioritization to meet monthly Go-Live timeline.
- Performed monthly audits on all deployed items in the Production environment while aligning the process with the SOX compliance standards.

## **Expeditors,** Business Operations Analyst ♂

July 2018 - March 2020 | Seattle, WA, USA

- Conducted thorough weekly analyses of branch operations to ensure current activities stay in compliance with the standard KPIs.
- Assisted internal clients with project optimization by identifying problems, developing solutions, and proposing recommendations.
- Developed complex SQL queries to produce 2+ reports/day to aid in departmental operations.
- Implemented process automation to boost operational productivity, which reduces manual labor by 90%.
- Managed 8 KPIs by capturing data, building reports, and tracking the performance using Power BI, resulting in a KPI improvement of 30%.

## **A EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

## Northwest Harvest, Volunteer

February 2018 - March 2018 | Seattle, WA, USA

 Aided in reducing homelessness and carrying out the "Free Food for All" campaign in Seattle areas by sorting, repacking, and distributing food on the grocery line.

## Maastricht Week of Entrepreneurship, Volunteer

October 2017 – November 2017 Maastricht, Limburg, Netherlands

- Generated ideas throughout event planning processes.
- Liaised with co-volunteers to facilitate workshops for guest speakers.
- Deepened cultural competency/intelligence by working with diverse volunteer groups.

# **United Way of King County,** *Intake and Benefits Specialist* January 2016 – April 2016 | Auburn, WA, USA

- Helped provide free tax filing services for low-income individuals and families throughout the "free tax campaign."
- Assessed and screened client background information while assisting with filling out tax paperwork.
- Connected clients to additional support benefits based on tax filing status and income threshold.